

Alisson Fogaça Software QA Engineer

+34 647 04 82 60

□ alisson\_fogassa@hotmail.com

32 years old

Skype: live:alisson fogassa

Madrid, Spain

% https://fogaca.net

My name is Alisson Fogaça and I live in Madrid, Spain. My educational background consists of a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science, Graduate Degree in Technologies for Web Applications and a degree in Computer Education. I have been working with software tests for about 13 years, having experience in: Software quality assurance for REST API (backend) and web/desktop applications (frontend) in betting, gambling, accounting, finance and real estate; Functional, non-functional, technical, acceptance, reliability, system, integration, usability, regression, security and performance tests; Tests automation development for REST API with Java, Spring, REST Assured, Supertest and Cucumber; Tests automation development for web applications with JavaScript, Cypress and Cucumber; Utilization of agile methodologies such as Scrum and Kanban, and platforms like Jira, Zephyr, Jenkins, Elastic, Couchbase, Kafka, AWS and Git; Web application development with PHP, JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, HTML and MySQL database; I worked as a lead and computer teacher. I have a confident and committed professional profile, besides, experience in working with goals and deadlines. I strive to push myself out of my comfort zone; I'm always improving and learning through new challenges and studies.



# **Experience**

## **Software QA Engineer**

#### Kindred

February 2023 – present

Responsible for software quality assurance for several backend API and frontend web applications in betting and gambling. Test automation development for web applications and API with JavaScript, Cypress, Cucumber and Supertest. Functional, acceptance, reliability, system, integration, usability, regression, security and mobile tests with iOS and Android. Tests on SQL and noSQL databases. Utilization of agile methodologies such as Scrum and Kanban, and platforms/technologies as Jira, Zephyr, BrowserStack, Elastic, Couchbase, Kafka and Git. In charge of the training creation and presentation for users, traders and customers.

### **QA Lead**

#### Matera

January 2021 – February 2023

Responsible for software quality assurance for REST API backend and web applications (frontend) in accounting and finance. Led a QA team directly. Test automation development for REST API with Java, Spring, REST Assured and Cucumber. Functional, acceptance, reliability, system, integration, usability, regression, security, and performance tests with jMeter and Postman. Tests on MySQL e H2 databases. Utilization of agile methodologies such as Scrum and Kanban, and platforms as Jira, Zephyr, Jenkins, AWS, and Git. Development of tools and scripts in PHP for software test support. Documentation for customers.

# **Software QA Engineer**

### **Thomson Reuters**

July 2012 - January 2021

Responsible for software quality assurance for several applications in accounting and real estate. In charge of the creation, preparation and execution of scripts and tests cases, besides the utilization and application of the database language SQL. Oversaw white and black box tests, and the utilization of Sybase SQL Anywhere 9 and 16 databases. Responsible for creating and presentations for users and customers, web applications tests and utilization of test automation and performance tools.

#### **IT Teacher**

## Government of Santa Catarina

February 2016 – December 2016 and August 2011 – June 2012

Responsible for teaching computing classes for young students in Windows and Linux environment at state schools. In charge of helping teachers and employees in the utilization of electronic devices such as computers.

#### **Help Desk**

## Criciúma City Hall

January 2010 - August 2011

Responsible for creating and maintaining networks and subnetworks, as well as assembling, setting and maintaining computers, servers, and printers. Dealt with clients and users through in-person services and over the phone, besides having broad knowledge on Windows and Linux environment installation and software maintenance.

## Education

# **Degree in Computer Education**

Universidade do Estado de Santa Catarina – UDESC August 2017 - August 2021

## **Graduate Degree Technologies for Web Applications**

Universidade Norte do Paraná – UNOPAR

August 2014 - August 2015

# **Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science**

Universidade do Extremo Sul Catarinense – UNESC February 2010 - July 2014

# Languages

Portuguese: Native, mother tongue

**English:** Reading, writing, listening, and speaking: C1 level Spanish: Reading, writing, listening, and speaking: B2 level



## **Skills**

Test Automation	
Manual Testing	
Test Strategy	
Test Management	
Java	
JavaScript	
Software Development	
Leadership	

REST API testing	REST Assured	Cucumber	BDD	Cypress
Elastic	Kafka	Couchbase	Supertest	Mobile testing
Spring Appium	Gherkin	BrowserStack	Git	BitBucket
Jira	Zephyr	Jenkins	Xcode	JMeter
Postman	Lombok	Docker	Maven	AWS
MySQL	Postgres	H2	Charles	Android Studio
Xcode	Visual Studio Code	IntelliJ	Junit	RabbitMQ
Team Work	Customers	Support	Selenium	Scrum
Kanban	jQuery	CSS	HTML	Bootstrap